This is far enough.
Oh? You don't
need an escort, then?
I could do without one
who wants to kill me.
You impress me.
It seems you know enough
to sense hostility, at least.
Rin has ordered me
to escort you peacefully,
so I will refrain
from attacking you.
In the face of absolute despair
That nearly burned
our hearts away
You still found the
courage to smile
Like you accepted it all
I lost my voice
And the things I wanted to say
But every time I
fell to my knees
I stood up and kept walking
We were looking for
the ideal white future
Our one and only hope
Now I may be left with nothing
But these raging
emotions that have
Nowhere to go
Still, I'll look for a new dawn
With more than one right answer
I won't stop
Until I find it
Is that so?
But if you want to go,
I'm happy to take you on.
I may be inexperienced,
but I am still a mage.
Don't be absurd.
Mirage
A mage who doesn't reek of
blood is worse than a novice.
You're saying that I don't
have the smell of blood on me?
Mages are beings who become cold-blooded
in order to achieve their goals.
You should follow
Tohsaka Rin's example.
She might have a soft spot or two, but she
has the proper mindset, despite her age.
It's fortunate for you that
Tohsaka's your Master.
She's your best shot
at getting the Grail.
That malevolent treasure chest
that can grant human wishes?
I have no interest
in such a thing.
No interest?
Don't Servants fight in
this war to have a wish
fulfilled that they
couldn't achieve in life?
Hardly.
We're summoned with
no say in the matter.
We Servants have no free will.
Your Saber is probably the only one
who answers the call of her own volition.
Only Saber?
That's right.
Heroic Spirits are called
forth by others' wills.
We're nothing more
than disposable tools.
Do you honestly believe that, in our
heart of hearts, we wish to help humans?
Well...
Listen.
Heroic Spirits are
mere instruments...
tools summoned to aid the disadvantaged and
disappear once their purpose is fulfilled.
They're sweepers, stripped of their
will and made to serve humans forever.
That is what Heroic Spirits are.
So-called "guardians" that are
summoned when it's convenient.
Instruments? What
are you talking about?
Saber is a person.
If she doesn't want to do
something, she refuses,
and I'm sure she can make her
own decisions now that she's here.
Possibly.
Being provided with a
Servant's shell in itself
allows Heroic Spirits
to regain their humanity.
Along with old
obsessions and regrets.
Regrets?
Put yourself in the shoes of those
who died with unfinished business,
only to find themselves brought
back by a human to do their bidding...
all because they seek the Grail.
Then why aren't you interested
in something so powerful?
I had no dream
that went unfulfilled.
I fulfilled my dream, died,
and became a Heroic Spirit.
So I have no wish
I want granted.
I'm home.
Welcome back, Senpai.
Hey. Welcome back, Shirou.
Saber-chan was
really mad at you.
Yeah...
You know about Mitsuzuri-san?
They found her
a little while ago.
They found Mitsuzuri?
Wait, how did you
know about that?
Ah, Ryuudou-kun
asked me to tell you.
He said her memory's
a bit jumbled,
but there's no visible trauma and
her condition isn't life-threatening.
Isn't that great news, Senpai?
Yeah.
Sakura, do you have a minute?
It isn't safe after dark, so I want
you to spend the night here again.
Actually, if possible, could you
keep staying here for a while?
Sorry. Am I putting
you on the spot?
Okay...
Um, I'll take you up
on your kind offer.
Shirou.
You gave me your word that
you would return before sunset.
I'm sorry.
You have every
right to be angry.
But before you yell at me, do you
mind if we discuss our strategy first?
There was a third
Master at school.
So Tohsaka and I agreed to form
a truce until we can identify them.
Are you opposed to
working with Tohsaka?
No.
I merely wish you had consulted me
before making such an important decision.
Oh... Sorry.
Just to be clear...
After this Master at
your school is defeated,
your truce with Rin
will be null and void.
Is that correct?
Yes.
As long as you understand
that, I have no objection.
Let us work with Rin so that you
may gain more combat experience.
Saber, you need
the Grail, right?
Yes.
But why do you need it?
Does this question have any
bearing on our future strategy?
No, I just...
Did something happen, Shirou?
Forget it. It's nothing.
I would like to
offer a suggestion.
Moving forward, you should build
experience through hands-on training.
Yeah, you're right.
Thanks in advance.
Hey, Emiya!
Did you hear about Mitsuzuri?
They told me at the
dojo just this morning.
She was found in Shinto, huh?
In a back alley, no less.
I heard her eyes were glazed
over and her uniform was in tatters.
I don't know what happened,
but how did a stuck-up girl like her
end up ditched in an alley like that?
As a friend, I can't help but...
Shinji!
Wow, scary.
I'm just kidding.
It's only a rumor, right?
But after yesterday, she's become
pretty infamous among the first-years.
You were the last person to
see Mitsuzuri, weren't you?
Yeah, but all we did
was make idle chitchat.
Don't jump to conclusions, now.
If you throw around false
accusations, you'll regret it, Emiya.
You're asking how
to identify a Master?
If you were near a
Master, would you know?
I suppose, but only if they hadn't
made any attempt at hiding it.
A Master is a mage, so if you follow
their mana, you can locate them.
But the most you'd
get is suspects.
That's all.
Emiya-kun?
Trace on.
There really is one here.
I'm impressed.
That's a sigil?
Yeah.
Emiya-kun, for a guy who has no
sensitivity to living organisms' mana,
you're surprisingly good at
picking up local abnormalities.
Was that a compliment?
You didn't think I was a
mage either, remember?
Why was that?
What? You want
me to spell it out?
No, forget it.
I can guess.
Clever boy.
Anyway, that's just how it is.
Mages only recognize people with
a certain level of mana as mages.
I thought it would be
something like that.
That should be most
of the active sigils.
You were able to disable
the magic field, then?
The field itself is already in place,
so all I did was weaken its potency.
Anyone who'd put
up a field like this
isn't going to stand by
and let others interfere.
I expect they'll show
themselves—maybe even tomorrow.
You think so?
Anyway,
I have other business to
see to, so I'm heading home.
I need to buy some
supplies for tomorrow.
You should head
home early today too.
What? Are you worried about me?
Th-That's not it!
We have an alliance now,
so if anything happens
to you, it'll spoil my plans.
That's all it was! I
just said it to be clear!
Heading home so late after
all that tedious sigil-erasing?
What did you say?
The magic field you've been
systematically dismantling
is an insurance policy
I set up for myself.
I knew it, Shinji. You're...
Please don't be so stiff, Emiya.
Just like you, I don't have any
mana, but they're making me a Master.
So what's the
story with that field?
I told you, it's just insurance.
Then are you the one who
attacked that student yesterday?
I didn't have any choice there.
My Servant did it on her own.
Come on, you have to believe me.
I don't want to fight anyone.
All right.
Wait, Emiya!
Will you team up with me?
My family, the Matous,
was once a lineage of mages.
The Matous?
Well, it's no surprise that you wouldn't
know, since you aren't a proper mage.
If you don't believe
me, ask Tohsaka.
Shinji, does Sakura
know about you?
Mage families only pass down
their secret arts to the eldest son.
As if anyone would teach
magic to that dunce of a girl.
Well? What do you say?
If you aren't going to do anything,
what's the point of working together?
So teaming up's a no-go, huh?
Emiya, don't tell me
you're actually in this to win.
I see.
Well, I can hardly leave
my sister in the home of
one who's taking part
in this slaughter, can I?
Fine.
I'll tell Sakura myself.
Okay. I'm glad you care for
her so much as her senior.
What we discussed here is
just between you and me, right?
I came clean out of
respect for our friendship.
Sure, I'll keep quiet.
You're wide open!
Okay, one more match!
Ouch...
Damn Saber.
When she decides to do
something, she doesn't hold back.
Trace on.
Crap. Concentrate!
Shirou?
What is it, Saber?
Nothing. I just sensed magic.
You are training?
Yeah. I do this every day.
May I enter?
Sure.
I heard that your magical
specialty is fortification.
It's the only thing I can do, so I'm
not sure if "specialty" is the word.
How does one train in
the art of fortification?
Fortification isn't just about
increasing a thing's toughness.
It also includes
increasing its effectiveness.
For this rock, it's
making it harder.
For that light bulb,
it's making it brighter.
I visualize an
object's components
and pass my mana
through them to fortify it.
I understand.
I-It's better to show than tell.
I'll try it on this.
Trace on.
Tracing fundamental structure.
Tracing auxiliary components.
Altering fundamental structure.
Reinforcing
auxiliary components.
Damn, another bust.
My success rate is
actually pretty low.
No, I sensed just now that
your concentration was lacking.
Oh...
No, my luck is a lot better
with bladed tools like this.
I can see that my presence
here is a distraction.
Please try not to
push yourself too hard.
I won't. Goodnight.
Is this...
Ryuudou Temple?
Yes, it is.
Mmm... Roasted cod roe...
Shirou.
The Caster-class Servant?
Indeed I am, Master of Saber.
Do not bother.
Once cast, a spell cannot be
washed away with the water of mana.
Especially not by the flow from
magic circuits as feeble as yours.
Meaning that I was
easy to summon here?
Because, of all the Masters,
you are the weakest by far.
You're going to kill me?
Rest easy. If I killed you, I wouldn't
be able to drain you of mana.
I did inadvertently kill a few
before I had the feel for it,
but now, I can collect
just the right amount.
You're the one behind
the people fainting in town?
Oh, you didn't know?
We Servants of the Caster class have
the prerogative of establishing territory.
By building a sanctuary here,
I've protected myself from you.
You can see it, can't you?
The mana of hundreds of
people stored in this soil...
The fragments of the rabble.
Caster... You
involved outsiders?
All the people in this
town belong to me.
Caster!
Well, I think we have
talked for long enough.
Let's get those
Command Spells off you.
A magic field that repels the
very concept of Heroic Spirits?
If I may:
what class of Servant are you?
The Assassin-class Servant,
Sasaki Kojirou.
Isn't it natural to identify
oneself before combat?
If my opponent should
identify themselves,
I am honor-bound as
a knight to do the same.
Once I have done so, I
will make you step aside.
My name is...
It matters not.
My blade will tell me all I
need to know of my enemy.
If you wish to pass, then
force your way through.
You want to take
my Command Spells?
That's right.
I will transplant them
onto my own Master.
And then, he will have Saber deal
with that troublesome Berserker.
Removing Command Spells also
requires extracting your magic circuits.
That's a good boy.
I do enjoy it when you struggle.
I expected to find
you long dead,
but it seems you're more
tenacious than I'd thought.
You...
Why?
Oh, I merely happened by.
So, are you able to move now?
My arrows should have
severed Caster's threads.
Yeah, I can.
Good to hear.
As much as I would like
to say, "Do what you want,"
I suggest you stay
where you are for now.
If you act without thinking...
You are Archer?
Damn that Assassin!
What is he doing?
See? She'll take
her anger out on you.
A woman's fury is
difficult to control.
Damn.
I think things are
about to get a bit violent.
We didn't understand anything
My left hand groped for
things that vanished to my touch
A moral conflict
stays your hand
and tricks you
out of your future
I don't know how
to protect anyone,
and my ideals might
well be pointless,
but I want to live my life
The past repeats before my eyes
Here I will trust the me
that now stands with you
Until my dream
crumbles and withers,
I hope you will carve
out paradise with me
Fight your fate
I wouldn't want your
help, even if you offered!
If you're both an idiot and
a child, you're a lost cause.
I shall mete out an appropriate punishment
upon those who would call me a witch.
A Servant who created a technique
on par with a Noble Phantasm...
The Reward for the Death Match
Next Time
Shall I break open that
belief with brute force?